Gin Tama
Fight fair...
♪♪～
Fair?
[Lake Toya]
(武士)うりゃ～っ！
♪♪～
Gimme a break!
(武士)いざ 尋常に…｡
Ah! He's getting away! He's running for his life!
(銀時)ﾌﾝ… 尋常に…？
Get him!
♪♪～
Since the Sword Ban nobody does this chanbara stuff anymore!
ﾌｯ 冗談じゃねえ！
Gintoki Sakata. Trademark: naturally-wavy hair.
ああっ 逃げた！ 脇目も振らずに
逃げやがった！ 追え!!
Has a sweet tooth and high blood-sugar. And he's kinda the main character.
ﾌｯ 廃刀令のご時世に➡
ﾁｬﾝﾊﾞﾗなんて
流行らねえっつうの！
＜坂田 銀時｡ 天然ﾊﾟｰﾏがﾄﾚｰﾄﾞﾏｰｸ｡
Stop!
Sorry, but I have a TV show to watch at four.
甘いものが大好きで
血糖値高めの➡
この物語の 主人公みたいな人＞
Gin!
Shinpachi?
よっ…！
(武士たち)待て～!!
Gin, help me!
悪い｡ ｵﾚ ４時から➡
Shinpachi Shimura. The straight man.
観たいﾃﾚﾋﾞがあるんで…｡
(武士たち)ああっ…！
Working for Gintoki in hopes of finding the samurai spirit.
≪(新八)銀さ～ん!!
ん？ 新八？
Hey, why are you letting them chase you like that?
銀さん 助けて～!!
＜志村 新八｡ ﾂｯｺﾐ担当｡
I don't know! Nobody wants to be chased!
侍魂を 学ぶため
銀時のもとで働いている＞
Anyway, run for it!
Stop!
おいおい 何 前ぶれもなく
追われてんだ？ この野郎｡
誰も 好き好んで
追われてるわけじゃないですよ！
とにかく逃げるぞ！
待て ｺﾗ～！
♪♪～
We've got you now...  Whoa!
Gin! There's no one here!
(２人)うわ～っ！
Kagura. Member of the "Yato Clan", the most powerful warrior race in the universe. She's cute but has a sharp tongue.
ああっ…！
ﾌｯﾌｯﾌｯﾌ｡
ここで会ったが ひゃ… あ～っ!!
(神楽)銀ちゃん
こっちには いなかったｱﾙ｡
Um...
＜神楽｡
宇宙最強戦闘民族 夜兎族の１人｡
What's this?
Sadaharu, Kagura's pet. A mysterious, giant space creature.
かわいらしい外見とは裏腹に
結構 毒舌＞
Geez, pay attention! I think they're pissed.
(武士)あのぅ… 何？ これ｡
K-Kagura. You'd better get out of here!
＜定春｡ 神楽のﾍﾟｯﾄ｡
謎の 巨大宇宙生物＞
おい 少しは 空気読め｡
なんか 怒ってるみたいだよ～！
Hurry up, "Lady's Four" is about to start.
か… 神楽ちゃん…
早く逃げたほうがいいよ～！
The host, Toshio Shiba, will wait for us!
After them!
(神楽)えっ？
Hold it!
No!
早くしないと 『ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４』
始まっちゃうｱﾙ｡
(神楽)柴 俊夫が待ってるｱﾙよ～!!
(武士たち)うぉ～っ!!
A dead end...
(武士)待て ｺﾗ～！
(神楽)待たないｱﾙ！
♪♪～
End of the line for you.
What are you talking about? We let you catch us.
行き止ま… わぁっ！
(神楽)り？
You should be thankful!
What? You losers!
You're the ones running all over town. You should talk!
(武士たち)ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
とうとう追い詰めたぞ！
何 言ってやがる｡
What group do you belong to?
Anyway, you're the spy who came to find our secret.
追い詰められてやったんだよ｡
ありがたく思えよ！
Before we cut you down, I'll ask you again. Who are you?
何それ？ 負け惜しみ？
さんざん逃げ回っといて
何 言ってやがる！
どこの手の者だ！
Who are we?
Hah...   All right, since you asked...
どうせ 我らの秘密を探りにきた
密偵であろう！
斬り捨てる前に聞いておこう！
お前たち いったい何者だ!?
We do anything from housework to finding missing persons!
If you're in trouble, just come to us!
何者だ～？ ﾌｯ しかたねえ
だったら教えてやるよ！
We'll take any case. We'll take any kind of job as long as we get paid.
家事手伝いから 人探しまで
なんでもござれ！
We're Odd Jobs Gin!
困ったことがあったら
ここに 来るｱﾙ！
Odd Jobs? You mean, you'll do anything?
一事が万事 金さえもらえば
なんでもやるよ～！
I see. That's why you snuck into our factory facility and...
万事屋銀ちゃんとは…！
(銀時/新八)ｵﾚたちのことだ！
(神楽)私たちのことだ！
万事屋？ 要するに
何でも屋ってこと？
There it is!
ﾌﾝ なるほどな！ それで我らが
工場施設に忍び込み…｡
That must be it!
That's Kuromi of Yamatoya!
Come on. Have some pickled seaweed.
(ｸﾛﾐ)ﾆｬ～ｵ｡
いたｱﾙ！
Hey, you damned cat! Wait!
間違いない あれが大和屋さんちの
ｸﾛﾐちゃんですよ！
They were looking for a cat?
ﾁｯﾁｯﾁ～
ほ～ら 酢こんぶあげるよ｡
おい ｸｿ猫 待ちやがれ～！
(武士たち)おぉ～っ！
(武士)猫を探してたのか…｡
[Hi, nice to meet you. Welcome to the anime series, Gin Tama.]
[It's written as "Gin" for silver and "Tama" for soul.]
[Don't write "Kin Tama" by accident, because that means "testicles"!]
[We're gonna kick off with a one hour special!]
[The Plot Thus Far]
The land of the samurai. There was a time, long ago, when our country was called by that name.
With the arrival of the "Amanto" from outer space and the Sword Ban twenty years ago,
the samurai class fell into decline.
In such hard times, there was one man left with the spirit of the samurai. His name is Gintoki Sakata.
Kagura and I, Shinpachi Shimura, work at Odd Jobs Gin, which is coincidentally run by this guy.
Which reminds me, we've been working for him for about a year now, but I don't think he's paid us yet.
["You Jerks! And You Claim to Have Gin Tama?!"]
Mr. Kariya has arrived!
Yo!
I can't hear you! Again!
Still not enough! Care to try it again?
No, there's no time.
I see...
(仲居)ｶﾘﾔ様 ご到着です！
[Kariya                                     Shishimura]
Today's guest characters.
[Shimomoto                                   Puu]
(ｶﾘﾔ)おい～っす！
They're definitely not regulars.
(下元/ﾌﾟｰ)おい～っす！
Oh, hi, Mr. Kariya.
声が小さい！ もう１回！
Thank you for coming all this way.
おい～っす！
(ﾌﾟｰ/下元)おい～っす！
Dispense with the intros...  So, how is that matter we talked about going?
まだ小さい！ もう１回やるか？
Fine. Everything is going very well.
(獅子村)いえ あまり時間が
ございませぬ｡
First, please take a look at this proposal.
そうか｡
＜彼らは 今回のｹﾞｽﾄｷｬﾗ｡
The goal of the project...
ﾚｷﾞｭﾗｰなんかじゃ 決してない＞
"This project is... "
I have no idea what this means!
(下元)これはこれは ｶﾘﾔ様｡
(ﾌﾟｰ)わざわざのご足労
痛み入ります｡
Is this a presentation for the spring anime season or what?!
挨拶はいい｡
して 例の件はどうなっておる？
Please forgive me.
はい 事は順調に運んでおります｡
まずは この企画書を
ご覧ください｡
｢企画の狙いについて…
本企画は…｣って➡
There.
こんなもん見せられても
わかんねえんだよ～!!
(下元)ぐはっ！
(ｶﾘﾔ)春番のｱﾆﾒのﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝかよ～!!
The Shinsengumi. A special government police force.
Hijikata. Vice-chief of Shinsengumi. He's the brains.
申し訳ございません｡
Okita. One of the Shinsengumi's best swordsmen.
Yamazaki, sit-rep?
They're in a private meeting in the back room on the second floor.
Four of them: one Amanto, two businessmen and one tough-looking ronin...
(山崎)よっ…｡
＜真選組｡ 幕府の特殊警察である｡
Great...
Let's go!
副長の土方は 真選組の頭脳｡
Speaking of the Amanto device, which we obtained with Mr. Kariya's support...
We just finished assembling it at our secret factory. All we need to do is get it into position.
沖田は 組随一の 剣の使い手だ＞
(土方)山崎 状況は？
２階奥の一室で密談中｡
If this project succeeds, all of Edo will fall under my control.
４人のうち 天人１名 商人２名｡
それと
腕が立ちそうな浪人が１名｡
That's right, Mr. Kariya.
上等だ｡ いくぞ！
(戸を叩く音)
(仲居)ｷｬ～ｯ！
御用あらためである！
This is a raid!
It's the Shinsengumi!
(隊士)真選組だ！ 神妙にしろ!!
Everyone stay still!
Sogo! Come on!
総悟 来い！
(沖田)ﾍｲ！
Okay!
♪♪～
真選組だ～!!
Freeze, Shinsengumi!
ﾁｯ｡
《ｸﾞｯﾊﾞｲ 副長｡ あの世でﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞでも
すすってくだせえ》
Good-bye, Vice-chief. Hope you enjoy sucking on mayonnaise in the next world.
(発射音)
おい 総悟…➡
Hey, Sogo, what are you doing here?
ﾄﾞｻﾏｷﾞで 何さらしてやがる｡
ﾁｯ｡
Hey, were you trying to kill me?!
ﾁｯじゃねえ！
いっぺん死ぬか ｺﾗ～!!
いやだなぁ ｵﾁｬﾒですよ ｵﾁｬﾒ｡
いつものことじゃないですか｡
No way, it was a joke. A joke, you know?
I'm always doing that.
いつも ｵﾚを
つけ狙ってやがるのか お前は！
You mean you're always trying to kill me?!
それより 土方さん…➡
Anyway, Hijikata, it seems that all our efforts end in failure.
こりゃあ まったくの
空振りってﾔﾂですかね｡
いや… そうでもねえようだぜ｡
Well...
Not really...
[Odd Jobs Gin]
あ～あ｡ ｵﾚも もう➡
Ah...
I'm too old to be reading JUMP. But I just bought it.
『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』卒業しなきゃいけねえ
歳だよなぁ｡
けど… なんか つい
買っちゃうんだよなぁ｡
That's right, Gin.
銀ちゃん そうｱﾙよ｡
そんなもん読んだって➡
Reading manga like that won't fill your stomach. Your blood-sugar level will remain the same.
腹には 何もたまらないよ｡
血糖値も そのままｱﾙよ｡
I know, but I'm addicted to it.
けど そう思いながらも
こう なんか ｸｾになってるから➡
次はやめよう 次はやめようって
思いつつ…｡
I keep thinking I won't buy the next one, but...
銀さん このままじゃﾏｽﾞｲですよ｡
Gin, this doesn't look good.
だよなぁ やっぱ こんな歳で
『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』読んでるのは ﾏｽﾞｲよなぁ｡
I know. Someone my age shouldn't be reading JUMP.
たしかに お前のにぎった
おむすびは ﾏｽﾞｲ ｱﾙね｡
Yeah, and your onigiri taste terrible.
どっちも違うわ!!
これですよ これ！
That's not what I'm talking about!
Look at this!
A bankbook?
貯金通帳？
Hah, you can't fool me. You can't eat that.
ﾊﾝ ﾊﾞｶにするなよ！ そんなもん
腹の足しにもならないｱﾙ｡
食えなくなんだよ 米すらも!!
We won't be able to eat anything, not even rice!
残高が 限りなく透明に近くて
ﾌﾞﾙｰになってんだよ!!
Our balance is almost zero, so I feel really blue!
昨日も 結局 猫 捕まんなくて
ﾀﾀﾞ働きだったんだから～!!
We failed to catch the missing cat yesterday, so it was all for nothing!
慌てんじゃねえよ｡
Calm down. You're the little punk who failed to buy JUMP, are you?
『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』買い逃がした
わんぱく坊主ですか？
金がねえのは 慢性の
鼻炎みたいなもんだろうが！
Having no money is just a condition, like chronic nasal infection, you know?
ｵﾚたちゃ 金欠と つかず離れず
なまぬる～く➡
Get used to it. Having no money is our destiny.
つきあっていかなきゃいけねえ
ﾃﾞｨｽﾃﾆｰなんだよ！
ｱﾝﾀ 何 開き直ってんの！
You think you're being defiant? I'm not talking about JUMP! I said we're in a pinch!
『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』じゃなくて ﾋﾟﾝﾁなんだよ｡
危険なんだよ！
明日から ﾊﾟﾝの耳すら
ご馳走なんだから～｡
Even bread crust would be like a feast tomorrow!
(地響き)
これは…？
This is...
鼻炎？
地震だ ﾎﾞｹ～！
A nasal infection?
It's an earthquake, moron!
(地響き)
おさまったようだな｡
It stopped.
We're having a lot of earthquakes lately.
なんか 最近 多いですね 地震｡
Yeah. It's shaking like a high school boy who has to simultaneously confront all five girls who asked him out.
あぁ｡ ５人同時に告られた
男子高校生みたいに➡
揺れに揺れまくってるな｡
(神楽)普通 ありえない
ｼﾁｭｴｰｼｮﾝ ｱﾙね｡
As if that ever happens.
But it could happen in JUMP.
けど 『ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』には あるんだよなぁ｡
(玄関のﾁｬｲﾑ)
Customer?
(神楽)お客さんｱﾙか？
まさか｡ どうせ 新聞の勧誘だろ｡
It can't be. It's probably a newspaper salesman or something.
新八 日経以外だったら➡
Shinpachi, if he's from anywhere other than the Nikkei, tell him that we subscribe already and send him away.
日経 取ってるから って
追い返しとけ｡
日経だったら 朝日のように
さわやかに追い返すｱﾙ｡
And if he is from Nikkei, send him away gently, like the rising sun.
(玄関のﾁｬｲﾑ)
は～い！
Yes, I'm coming!
はいは～い
新聞なら 間に合ってますよ～｡
We're already subscribed to a newspaper.
ん…？
Huh?
(加藤)ﾍｯｸｼｮｲ！
あのぅ…？
Um...
ここは 頼まれれば
何でもやってくれる➡
I'm here because I heard you guys will take any job.
万事屋と聞いてきたのですが…｡
No...
Shinpachi, what are you doing? "Lady's Four" is about to start!
(神楽)新八～ 何やってるｱﾙ？
(神楽)早くしないと
『ﾚﾃﾞｨｽ４』始まっちゃうｱﾙよ｡
ここは 万事屋と
聞いてきたのですが…｡
I heard this is Odd Jobs Gin.
...frigging...
どうした？ そんな
とんちの効いた勧誘なのか？
What's wrong? Can't get rid of this guy?
いざとなったら 実力行使も
辞さないぞ～ とか言って…｡
He's not trying to strongarm you, is he?
万事屋ですよね？
This is Odd Jobs, right?
...way!
ﾊﾞ…！
ｶ…！
な…!!
No...
...frigging...
...way!
もし？ もし？ お三方…？
Hello? Hello? Hey, all three of you.
ｱ… ｱﾝﾀ まさか… 依頼人!?
You can't be...
Are you a client?!
Ken Kato. Ronin. This episode's client.
＜加藤 健｡ 浪人｡ 今回の依頼人＞
Let me introduce myself. My name is Ken Kato. I've been a ronin for a few days now.
申し遅れました
私 加藤 健と申します｡
つい先日から 浪人やってます｡
おいおい いったい
何があったってんだ？
Hey, what's going on?
２日連続で 依頼がくるなんて
ｽﾍﾟｼｬﾙ以外 ありえないよ｡
We've had clients two days in row?! Must be a special version of the show!
そ… そそそ… 粗茶でございます｡
H-Here's some tea for you.
Hot!
ｱﾁﾁ…！ あ… あのぅ…｡
Oops!
Um...
冷やかしだったら
許さないからな！
You're really in for it if this is a joke!
何？ 動揺して ｹﾝｶ腰!?
What? You're shocked and getting uppity?
依頼の内容は？
So what can we do for you?
はい… 私は なくしたものを
取り戻したいんです｡
Well, I... want to get something back that I lost.
すっぽり抜け落ちた大切なものを
取り戻したいんですよ…｡
Something very important to me.
あのぅ… なくしたものって
いったい 何なんですか？
Well, what did you lose?
それが 3,000万円ほどあれば
取り戻せるんですけど…｡
Well...  I need about thirty million yen to get it back.
Listen, baldy! I said you were in for it if this was a joke, remember?!
こんのﾊｹﾞ！ 冷やかしだったら
許さない言うたの➡
もう忘れたｱﾙか!?
What's an easy way to earn money? Every time I grab it, it runs through my fingers...
楽して儲けるか…｡
いつも 手が届きそうになるたびに
こぼれ落ちてんだよなぁ…｡
Ah-ha, that's it! Every time you move your hand, we go further into the red!
そのせいか～！ 手ぇ回すたんびに
残高が この状態か～!!
いや… でも 困っていたら
どんな依頼でも 受けてくれる…｡
But I heard you would take any kinds of jobs for troubled people.
We can't even pay our rent now!
こっちは 家賃すら
まともに払えない状態よ！
人の面倒なんて 見てられないｱﾙ！
おととい来やがれ ｺﾝﾁｸｼｮｳ!!
There's no way we can take care of someone's business! Don't come here again!
２人して興奮してんじゃねえ｡
Calm down, both of you. So, what would you do with the money if you had it?
それよりｱﾝﾀ
その金 何に使うつもりだ？
１か月前 窓際族を卒業して
無職になりました｡
A month ago, I ended up as dead weight at the company and got laid off.
And three weeks ago, I was swindled and lost my house.
３週間前
うまい言葉に乗せられて➡
家を 土地ごと
だまし取られました｡
Then two weeks ago, my wife and daughter left me, without even leaving a note.
２週間前 手紙も残さず
妻が 娘を連れて出ていきました｡
(銀時たち)あ…｡
１週間前…｡
And one week ago...
(銀時たち)おぉ…！
(銀時たち)だぁ～っ!!
なんで そこでやめるの!?
気になるじゃん！
Why did you stop?!
Spit it out! Do tragedies like this befall you every single week?!
なに その１週間ごとに襲いかかる
超ﾊｰﾄﾞなｲﾍﾞﾝﾄの数々～!!
Tell us what happened to you last week!
(神楽)先週は いったい
何が起こったｱﾙか!?
続き… 聞きたいですか？
Would you... like to hear the rest?
Why will he tell us the rest only after we complete the job?
続きは 依頼が完了したらって
どういうことｱﾙ？
っていうか この依頼
間違いなく 完了しないって｡
Whatever, I'm sure we won't be able to complete this job.
(加藤)あの…
どこへ行くのですか？
Um...
Where are we going?
ま なんだ…➡
All right...  The point is that we get the money as quickly as possible, right?
要するに 手っとり早く
金が入ればいいんだろ？
(お登勢)いらっしゃ…
なんだ お前たちかい｡
Welcome...  Oh, it's you guys.
＜ お登勢さん｡
Otose. Proprietor of Otose Snack House and Gintoki's landlord.
ｽﾅｯｸお登勢のｵｰﾅｰ
兼 万事屋銀ちゃんの大家さん＞
I see.
(お登勢)なるほどねぇ｡
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)あめえんだよ お前ら！
You guys are such dopes.
そんな方法あれば
泥棒なんて 最初から➡
If you could make money that quickly, there would be no thieves in the world! Idiots!
存在しないに決まってんだろ
この ｸｿﾎﾞｹが！
So says the ex-thief!
(神楽)お前 元 泥棒じゃねえか！
確かに｡
Indeed.
＜ｷｬｻﾘﾝ｡
Catherine. Works for Snack House Otose. She came to Earth as a migrant worker.
ｽﾅｯｸお登勢の従業員｡
出稼ぎで 地球へやってきた＞
Well, there might be one way...
ま 方法がないってことも
ないんだけどね｡
(医者)お客さん どれにしますか？
So, what'll it be?
Well...  Um...
(加藤)いや それは…｡
You've got two of those, so why don't you sell one?
２つあんだから
１つくらい いいじゃないか｡
You'd sell one if you were a real man!
男なら ﾄﾞﾝと売っときな！
ﾀﾞﾒだ こりゃ｡
This isn't gonna work.
なんだよ
ﾎﾝﾄ 口ほどにもねえなぁ｡
So disappointing. You're just a big talker.
ちゃらい覚悟で
金持ちになりたいなんて➡
It's not going to happen if you're not prepared, right?
ありえねえんじゃねえの？
Forget it. It won't happen.
いや 無理だから｡
普通に無理だから｡
(新八/神楽)…ん？
(銀時たち)あ…？
(さっちゃん)あら皆さん 偶然ね｡
Oh hello, everyone. Fancy meeting you here!
＜猿飛 あやめ｡ 通称 さっちゃん｡
Ayame Sarutobi. Nickname: Sachan. An elite ninja and a former a member of the Oniwabanshu.
元 お庭番衆の ｴﾘｰﾄ忍者＞
えっ？ 手っとり早く
お金を手に入れる方法？
What?
A way to get money quickly?
さっちゃんさん
いいから ﾒｶﾞﾈかけなよ｡
Sachan, why don't you put your glasses on?
周りの人にも 迷惑だからさ｡
You're getting on everyone's nerves. I don't care if your character looks like mine.
ﾎﾞｸ ｷｬﾗかぶっても
気にしないからさ｡
何 言ってるの？
What are you talking about?
I couldn't care less about you.
あなたなんて 米の粒ほども
気にしてなんかいないわ｡
私が気にしているのは…｡
All I care about is...
あなただけよ 銀さん｡
...you, Gin.
(定春)ﾊｸﾞ｡
See?! I told you it would help to put on your glasses!
だから ﾒｶﾞﾈかけろって
言ってんだろ～!!
(さっちゃん)そう… お金って➡
I see.
So the money you were talking about is not for the purchase of our little love nest?
私と銀さんの愛の巣を作る
資金ってわけじゃなかったのね｡
お前相手じゃ 愛の巣どころか➡
Our love nest?
Man, I can't even bear to think about sitting next to you at the diner.
定食屋で相席すら
ありえねえんだよ この野郎｡
Always so cold, as usual.
相変わらず 冷たいわね｡
But I don't give up so easily.
でも それくらいなら
私は ちっとも へこたれない｡
っていうか なんだよ その納豆｡
And what's with the natto, anyway?
[natto = fermented soy beans; popular as a diet food]
持ってりゃ ｷｬﾗ立ちすると
思ったら大間違いだよ ﾎﾝﾄ！
Just holding on to it isn't gonna help you you'll lose weight. Seriously.
Oh? Do you think that pushing me away is going to make me happy?
あら そうやって 更に突き放せば
私が喜ぶとでも思ってるの？
うだうだ言ってねえで
その納豆 なんとかしろや➡
Stop blabbering, and do something with the natto, you natto woman!
Here we go!
この納豆女！
…あぁ～っ！
That's it! Just like that!
(さっちゃん)
そうよ そのとおりよ｡
More! More! Just keep blasting away at me!
もっと…
もっと蔑めばいいじゃない｡
それが 私の糧になるの｡
それが 私を興奮させるの！
You're really turning me on!
何これ｡ 臭っ｡ この空気 何？
What's this? It stinks!
What's that smell?
Smells like natto and masochism.
納豆臭ｱﾙか？ Ｍ臭ｱﾙか？
はぁ… あっ｡
Kato.
(ﾌﾟｰ/下元)加藤～｡ ﾍﾍﾍﾍ…｡
(ﾌﾟｰ)よぅ加藤 元気にやってっか？
Yo, Kato. How's it going?
Well, uh...
(加藤)いや まぁ…｡
(ﾌﾟｰ/下元)ﾍﾍﾍﾍ…｡
I bet that was hard on you, huh?!
大変だったよなぁ｡
あんな契約書に ﾊﾝｺなんか押して｡
You put your seal on a contract like that? You'd better be more careful as to what you agree to.
印鑑 押すときは
気をつけねえとな｡
Too bad. We know you're hard up.
災難だったねぇ｡
ｵﾒｴ あれ以外にも➡
いろいろあったもんな｡
えっ どうして それを？
Huh? How did you know?
ﾊﾊﾊ… それより お前
今 何してんだい？
Anyway, what have you been doing lately?
Well, I'm trying to work hard and buy my house back...
はぁ… 家を買い戻すために
いろいろと…｡
Buy it back? That'll never happen.
家を買い戻す？ そりゃ無理だ｡
えっ？
Because...
なんたって あそこは…｡
おい｡
Hey...
W-Well...  That's right...
あ～ そうだったなぁ！
じゃあな 加藤｡
Well, let us know when you find a house.
家 見っかったら言えや｡
年賀状くらいは出してやっからよ｡
We'll at least send a New Year's card when you do, Kato.
(下元)風呂 入れよ！
Take a bath!
Brush your teeth!
(ﾌﾟｰ)歯みがけよ｡
(下元)また来週！
See you next week!
(さっちゃん)ねぇ あなた…｡
はい… うっ｡
Hey, you...
Yes?
Maybe you oughta rethink your request.
依頼の内容 変更なさい｡
I'm available for assassination jobs since I'm a professional killer.
暗殺なら請け負うわよ｡
ｱﾀｼ 職業 殺し屋だから｡
抹殺ｱﾙね！ 今すぐ 簀巻きにして
ﾄﾞﾌﾞ川に放り込むｱﾙ!!
Let's kill them!
Why don't we roll them up and throw 'em into the ditch now?!
No, wait.
いや 待ってください｡
依頼の内容は 変更します｡
I'm changing my request.
でも… 内容は 暗殺じゃない｡
But it's not going to be assassination.
I... want to be stronger!
私は… 強くなりたい｡
(３人)お安いご用！
We got it!
おい お前ら｡
(３人)ん？
Hey, everyone...
まぁ なんだ…➡
Well, at any rate, we can jack up his hit points another hundred or so.
とりあえず ﾋｯﾄﾎﾟｲﾝﾄは
100くらい上げとけよ｡
って 銀さんは
どうするつもりなんですか？
So where are you going, Gin?
ｵﾚは ｵﾚで やることがあるんだよ｡
I have something to take care of.
That's all.
(土方)というわけだ｡
(近藤)ほぅ…｡
I see.
(近藤)これが
その設計図ってﾔﾂか｡
Oh, so this is a blueprint...
＜近藤 勲｡
泣く子も黙る 真選組局長である＞
Isao Kondo. Commander of the Shinsengumi. Strikes fear in the hearts of others.
(近藤)ところで 土方…｡
ん？
By the way, Hijikata...
見ても さっぱり
わからんのだが…｡
I have no idea what this says...
(土方)さっきから
天人のｶﾗｸﾘの設計図だって➡
I've been trying to explain that this is a blueprint for an Amanto device, Kondo!
説明してんだろうが
近藤さんよ…！
I see. Some sort of device...
あぁ そうか｡ 何かのｶﾗｸﾘか｡
そのｶﾗｸﾘで
何か とんでもねえ悪事を➡
Yes, and someone seems to be planning to use that device for some heinous deed here in Edo.
企んでいるﾔﾂらが
この江戸にいるって話だ｡
はっ…｡ おい ﾄｼ…｡
Toshi...
悪事って何だ？
What does "heinous deed" mean?
(土方)はぅっ！
さっきから 何 聞いてんだ ｺﾗｧ!!
You haven't heard a word I said!
♪♪～
[Drift Star Embassy]
《大使館…？》
An embassy?
Gintoki.
(桂)銀時｡
ﾂﾞﾗ｡
Zura?
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ 桂だ｡
It's not Zura. It's Katsura.
＜桂 小太郎｡ 攘夷志士｡
Kotaro Katsura. Member of the exclusionist rebels. An activist trying to rid Edo of aliens called Amanto.
江戸の町から
天人と呼ばれる宇宙人を➡
排除しようとしている活動家｡
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡ っつうか 何これ!?＞
Elizabeth. What the hell is this?
Gintoki, what are you doing here?
(桂)銀時…
こんな所で 何をしている？
Well...  you know, jogging, taking a walk, something like that... I'm not really sure, you know...
いやぁ まぁ… 気分的には
ｳｫｰｷﾝｸﾞとｼﾞｮｷﾞﾝｸﾞの中間の➡
なんか よくわからない感じの
ことをしているような…｡
Very well.
なら よいのだが…｡
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ？
最近 この辺りで➡
I heard some dangerous rumors around here.
物騒な噂を耳にしてな｡
噂？
Rumors?
近々 江戸を
丸ごと壊滅せんと企んでいる➡
I've heard about an Amanto who's plotting to destroy all of Edo.
天人がいるという噂だ｡
天人が
なんで そんなこと考えるんだ？
Why would an Amanto do something like that?
(桂)知らん｡
だが それが本当ならば➡
I don't know...  But if it's true, we must punish them.
天誅を加えるまでの話｡
(桂)銀時 何をしようとしているか
知らんが 気をつけたほうがいい｡
Gintoki, I don't know what you're going to do, but you'd better be careful.
The Embassy is considered foreign soil.
大使館の中は
治外法権なのだからな｡
治外法権ねぇ｡
Foreign soil...
ｿｲﾂは気をつけねえとな｡
じゃあな ﾂﾞﾗ｡
I should be careful, then.
Later, Zura.
It's not Zura. It's Katsura.
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ 桂だ｡
♪♪～
その笠 流行ってんの？
That hat is so out of style.
ほわぁ～～ちゃっ!!
(岩が割れる音)
Okay! Why don't you give it a try?
ほら やってみるよろし｡
できるか～!!
He can't do that!
何 言ってるｱﾙ｡ 簡単ｱﾙよ｡
What are you talking about? It's easy!
Suppress your inner "self" and even you can look like Antonio Inoki.
心頭滅却すれば 顔まで猪木ｱﾙ｡
いや 意味わかんないし…｡
I have no idea what you're talking about.
じゃあ とりあえず
自由に打ち込んできてください｡
Okay, you can start any time.
で では…｡
Right...
やあぁ～～～… あぁっ!!
はぁ…｡
What? Your eyes are bloodshot. Were you up all night playing Tetris?
何ですか？ 目 血走らせて｡
徹夜で ﾃﾄﾘｽかい？
ﾌﾌﾌ… ｹﾞｰﾑは 今からやるんだよ｡
The game is just about to begin.
Give it a rest.
やめとけ｡
そんなｵﾓﾁｬ 振り回したって➡
Something bad could happen if you swing that toy around like that.
ろくなことねえよ｡
《ｺｲﾂ 仕込み杖に
気づいているのか？》
Did he notice my sword cane?
どうでもいいけどよぉ
なんで ｵﾚを狙うのかくらい➡
Whatever, but can you at least tell me why you're trying to kill me?
教えといてくんない？
(獅子村)笑止！
Don't play dumb! We already know you're nosing around.
貴様が この近辺を
嗅ぎ回ってることくらい➡
先刻 承知だ｡
あぁ それ違うって｡
Wrong. That was Zura. It wasn't me.
それは ﾂﾞﾗだ｡ ｵﾚじゃねえ｡
問答無用｡
No more discussion!
(地響き)
地震？
An earthquake?
でやぁ～～っ!!
でや～！
ｽｷだらけなんじゃ～！
You're leaving yourself wide open!
そんなんで強くなれると➡
You think you'll become stronger like that?! Dumbass!
思ってんのか ﾎﾞｹ～!!
ﾊｧ…｡
意外と激しいのね｡
You're surprisingly intense.
あっ すみません！
大丈夫ですか？
Ah, I'm sorry. Are you all right?
は はぁ…｡
Get up! Stand up! Katoken!
(神楽)立て～！ 立つんだ ｶﾄｹﾝ!!
いいｱﾙか？ ﾋｼﾞを
脇から離さないような感じで➡
Listen! Keep your elbows close to your body and strike, strike, and strike!
内側を えぐり込むように
打つべし 打つべし 打つべし!!
Wait! That's a jab.
ちょっと待って｡
それ ｼﾞｬﾌﾞの打ち方でしょ？
That won't work for tomorrow, right? It doesn't have anything to do with swordsmanship!
『あしたのために』でしょ？
剣術 関係ないじゃん｡
泪橋を 逆に渡るｱﾙよ｡
Cross Namida Bridge carefully!
(２人)はぁ…｡
(さっちゃん)
ここは 私の出番のようね｡
It looks like it's my turn.
私が 強くしてあげる！
I'll make you stronger!
もっと強く…｡
こうですか…？
Stronger!
L-Like this?
もっと… もっとよ！
はい…｡
More! More!
Oh yes!
That's it. Good!
そう… いい感じよ！
これでもかぁ～！
How about this?!
(さっちゃん)あなた
なかなか素質がありそうよ｡
You have potential.
What is this training for?
って 何の特訓だよ!?
いったい 何の素質があるんだよ！
What kind of potential does he have?!
(さっちゃん)女王様｡
As a dominatrix...
He's a man! Anyway, that's not the point!
男だろ！
っていうか それ以前の問題!!
Oh, you're very patient! You'll get another appetizer!
おぉ～ 我慢し放題ね！
おかず１品 増やしてもらうｱﾙよ｡
いいから 早くほどいてよ！
(加藤)あの…｡
Untie me now!
Um...
ありがとうございました｡
もう結構です｡
Thank you so much, but that's enough.
やっぱり 私には
強くなるなんて無理なんです｡
I don't think I'll ever get any stronger.
もう あきらめます｡
I give up...
え？ あの…｡
Huh? B-But...
So I'll just leave.
(加藤)では 私は これで｡
ｶﾄｹﾝ？
Katoken...
あ～あ 一張羅が台なしだよ｡
Boy, my best clothes... ruined. My mom is going to be really mad, you bastard!
母ちゃんに怒られんじゃねえか
この野郎｡
You'd better be more worried about your life than your clothes!
服の心配より
命の心配をしたらどうだ！
うりゃあ～～っ!!
Who is Shishimura, Gintoki's mysterious attacker?
＜銀時に襲いかかる
謎の刺客 獅子村｡
And what heinous deed is Kariya the Amanto planning?
そして 何を企むのか!? 天人 ｶﾘﾔ｡
Did Kato really give up?
加藤は 本当に
あきらめてしまったのか!?＞
あい～ん！
＜ というところで➡
It's time to say good-bye to those who live in a certain area.
一部の地域の皆さんは
ここで さよならだ！
For the rest of you, please keep watching!
一部の地域の人以外は
後半へ続く！＞
[To be continued]
♪♪～
やるねぇ ｱﾝﾀ｡
元 攘夷志士ってところか？
You've got some skill... Are you a former Exclusionist rebel?
そういうお前は 元ﾔﾝだろ？
And you're a former gangster, aren't you?
若いときに
髪の毛 傷めつけちゃ ﾀﾞﾒだぞ｡
You shouldn't have damaged your hair when you were young.
(獅子村)天然ﾊﾟｰﾏに
言われたくねえんだ ﾁｸｼｮｳ！
I don't have to take that from someone with naturally wavy hair!
傷つくなぁ｡
You're breakin' my heart...
It's not like I wanted wavy hair!
好きで ｸﾙｸﾙまわってるわけじゃ
ないんですけど！
次は 必ず仕留める｡ 覚悟！
I'll kill you this time! You'd better say your prayers!
ｼﾑﾗ～ 後ろ後ろ｡
Shimura! Look out behind you.
Hey! I'm not Shimura...
拙者は ｼﾑﾗではない！
Hey!
(警官)ｺﾗ～ 廃刀令の ご時世に
何やっておる～｡
We're still under the Sword Ban! What're you doing?
Um... Well...
え… いや その…｡
ﾅｲｽｷｬｯﾁ｡
Nice catch.
なんだ 余興の練習か｡
Oh, I see, sideshow practice...
ﾊﾊﾊﾊ… いや そうなんですよ｡
ﾎﾝﾄ なぁ おい！
Yes! Isn't that right?
Right? Huh? Where'd he go?
…いない｡
He's gone.
Hey, hey. You feeling nostalgic?
おいおい 青春ですか？
夕日に向かって➡
Trying to control the urge to run toward the sunset, you idiots?
駆け出したいのを抑えるので
いっぱいいっぱいか この野郎｡
銀さん！
銀さん ごめんなさい｡
Gin!
We have to apologize, Gin.
ｶﾄｹﾝ 帰っちゃった｡
Katoken left.
ｶﾄｹﾝ？ あぁ 依頼人のことか｡
Katoken?
Oh, our client.
っていうか
早く ほどいてくださいよ～！
Hey, get me down from here!
ま そんなもんだろ｡
ﾀﾀﾞ働きは いつものこったい➡
Ah well, so it goes.
We're getting used to working for nothing.
いちいち気にしてたら
きりねえよ｡
It's no use worrying about it.
(新八たち)え？
ｵﾚは ﾊﾅっから ﾀﾞﾒっぽいと➡
I had a feeling when we took the job that it wouldn't work out. Really.
思ってたんだよ ﾎﾝﾄ｡
銀さん！
Gin!
まったく…｡
Oh, well...
銀さんが あんなに
薄情者だったとは知らなかったよ｡
I didn't know Gin would be so cold-hearted.
いつものことｱﾙ｡
That's how he is.
He'll let anyone in, but doesn't stand in their way if they want to leave.
去る者は追わず
来る者も ほっとく｡
っていうか 神楽ちゃん
なんで ｳﾁにいんの？
By the way, Kagura, why did you come to my house?
なんで ｳﾁのお米 食べてんの!?
Why are you eating my rice?
Dinner is right next door.
隣の晩ごはん｡
隣じゃねえよ！
It's not next door!
(お妙)２人が
そんなことで どうするの？
Why would you two say something like that?
Sis...
姉上！
＜ お妙｡ 新八の姉｡
Otae. Shinpachi's big sister.
父の遺した
道場を守るため 現在 ｱﾙﾊﾞｲﾄ中＞
Works part-time in order to save the dojo her father left her.
あなたたちが信じてあげないで➡
If you don't believe in Gin, who will?
誰が 銀さんを
信じてあげられるの？
いや ｱｲﾂは そんな上等なもんじゃ
ありませんよ お妙さん｡
No! He doesn't deserve it, Otae.
昔から言うでしょ？
Like I've been saying,
you can't trust a guy who has the eyes of a dead fish.
死んだ魚のような目をした人間に
ろくなﾔﾂはいない って｡
ろくでなしは お前だ
この ｽﾄｰｶｰ野郎!!
You're the bastard! You stalker!
(神楽)まだ ｽﾄｰｷﾝｸﾞ
続いてるｱﾙか？
Is he still stalking her?
I'll finish you off!
あぁ｡ 説明するのも
面倒なくらいにね｡
Yeah, but it's hard to explain.
あ～ 銀さん
今頃 何してんのかなぁ？
I wonder what Gin is doing now.
[Higucchan Bar]
(戸の開閉音)
はぁ…｡
食うか？
You want some?
な 何ですか？ それ…｡
Wh-What's that?
It's Azuki ala Gintoki.  Rice with azuki beans.
あずきてんこ盛り
宇治銀時丼だ｡
け… 結構です｡
N-No thanks.
[Side Road to Enka]
(演歌)
酒は いいなぁ｡
This is good sake.
嫌なことを
いっとき忘れさせてくれる｡
Helps me forget all my worries for a moment.
だが 明日になれば
嫌でも思い出す｡
But I'll be reminded of them tomorrow.
そして それは 昨日よりも➡
And I think they'll be even bigger headaches than they were today.
もっと
つらくなってるんじゃねえのか？
逃げても
逃げ切れるもんじゃねぇ｡
It is not like you can run away from them.
特に…➡
Especially...
ﾎﾝﾄに忘れたいことからはな｡
...those things you really want to forget.
はぁ…｡
(加藤)言い訳が
したかったのかもしれません｡
I may have wanted an excuse.
言い訳？
An excuse?
言いましたよね？
I already told you that I was fired, my house was taken from me,
会社をｸﾋﾞになり 家を取られ
家族が出ていった って…｡
and my family left me, didn't I?
(加藤)それまで 私は➡
I used to be a salesman.
とある会社の
営業職をやっていました｡
家族のために働いて働いて…➡
I kept working for the sake of my family day after day...
ようやく ﾏｲﾎｰﾑを手に入れました｡
And we were finally able to buy our own house.
幸せでした｡
I was happy.
これからも
家族のためなら頑張れる…➡
I believed that I could keep working for them. But...
そう思っていたのですが…｡
わけが わかりませんでした｡
I still don't understand it.
特に何をしたわけでもないのに
いきなり 会社をｸﾋﾞになり➡
I didn't do anything wrong, but I was fired from the company.
ﾔｹになって
酔いつぶれたのを狙って➡
So, I went and got drunk,
and those guys stamped my seal on a contract without my permission.
無断で ｱｲﾂらは
契約書に 判を押したんです｡
勝手に判を押した
契約書を掲げて➡
Then the land shark came and showed us the bogus contract, saying I had to leave my house.
家から出てけ と
地上げ屋たちが押し寄せて…｡
My wife couldn't stand their harassment and left with my daughter.
地上げ屋の嫌がらせに
とうとう耐えられなくなって➡
妻は 子供を連れて
出ていきました｡
♪♪～
(加藤)毎週 事件が起きる と
言いましたよね？
I said that something happened to me every week, remember?
先週 何が起こったと思いますか？
さぁな｡
What do you think happened last week then?
I don't know.
手紙？
(加藤)えぇ｡
A letter?
Yes. My daughter sent me a letter right before my eviction.
立ち退き寸前にね…
娘が 手紙をくれたんですよ｡
♪♪～
(娘)｢お父さん わたし
はやく おうちにかえりたい｣
"Daddy, I want to come home soon."
♪♪～
それまでは すべてを
あきらめていたんですけど➡
By then, I had given up on everything.
この手紙を読んで➡
But after reading her letter, I wanted to give it another try.
少し 抗ってみたくなったのかも
しれません｡
Does that sound stupid?
(加藤)ﾊﾞｶみたいですよね…
家さえ取り戻せば また家族が➡
I believed that if I got my house back, my family would return.
元に戻るんじゃないかって
勝手に思い込んで…｡
でも もう わかりました｡
But now I realize...
やっぱり 私は ﾀﾞﾒなﾔﾂです｡
I'm useless.
私みたいなのが
どう あがいても…｡
行くぜ｡
Even though I worked so hard...
Let's go.
あ… あの…｡
(板前)ありがとうございました！
Um...
Thank you!
…ぐぅっ！
(板前)お客さん お勘定｡
Sir, your bill.
あのぅ… すみません｡
Um... Sorry, but since I'm unemployed, can we split the bill at least?
私 無職なもんでして
せめて ﾜﾘｶﾝに…｡
Let's go, Katoken!
さぁ行くぞ ｶﾄｹﾝ｡
(加藤)行くって…｡
Huh? To where?
え なに？
契約書 取り戻さなくていいの？
What? Don't you want to get the contract back?
そ それじゃあ！
Th-Then...
ｵﾚは 万事屋だ｡
何でもやって… うぅっ！
I'm Odd Jobs Gin. I'll do anything for...
おぇ～ 気持悪い…｡
I don't feel so good.
殴り込み 明日でいい？
Can we postpone the raid until tomorrow?
え…？
(地響き)
Huh?
Did I drink too much?
あ やっぱ飲み過ぎた？
頭が ｸﾞﾗｸﾞﾗ揺れてるよ～｡
My head feels like it's shaking.
No, this is an earthquake...I think.
違いますよ｡
これは 地震… ですかね？
おぇ… もう 限界～！
(吐く声)
Urgh! I can't hold it anymore!
な なんか 私も もらいｹﾞﾛ…｡
(吐く声)
I feel I'm going to throw up, too.
そんな おすそわけはいいから…
って言った先から うぅ～！
You don't have to...
(吐く声)
Man, what a headache.
あぁ 頭 痛え…｡
This is a total hangover.
完璧に二日酔いだな こりゃ｡
水 飲みてえ…｡
I need some water.
さすが 銀さん｡
こうなるんじゃないかと➡
Leave it to Gin.
I knew we would do something like this.
思ってたんですよ｡
何 言ってるｱﾙか｡
Really? You said Gin was cold-hearted, didn't you?
銀ちゃんのこと
薄情者とか言ってたくせに！
そういう神楽ちゃんだって
来る者もほっとく とか➡
What about you?
You said that he lets anyone in, didn't you?!
言ったじゃんか！
うるせえ｡
Shut up! Stop talking so loudly.
あんま 大声 出すんじゃねえよ｡
頭に響くじゃねえか｡
It really hurts my head.
Oh, here it is.
おぉ ここだ ここだ｡
ｶﾄｹﾝさんの契約書を
取り戻すんですよね？
We'll get Katoken's contract back, right?
どうやって忍び込むｱﾙか？
How do we sneak in?
Huh? We're not going to sneak in - we're going to break in.
あぁ？ 忍び込むんじゃねえよ
殴り込むんだよ｡
殴り込みってのはよ
正面から 堂々と➡
That means we'll storm in through the front.
入っていくもんだろうが！
ちょっと 銀さん!?
Gin...
ごめ～んくださ～～い!!
Knock knock!
ちょっと待っ…！
Wait!
Bunta! Are you trying to act like Bunta Sugawara?
(神楽)文太？
もしかして 文太気取り？
Hello! Anyone here?
お～い｡ 誰か いませんか～？
You don't need to let them know we're here.
って わざわざ
呼び出さなくたって…｡
おかしいですね
人の気配がしませんけど…｡
Strange. There doesn't seem to be anyone here.
♪♪～
(銀時たち)あっ…｡
まだ温かい｡
It's still warm. That is, like they just left!
ついさっきまで
人がいたってことですよ｡
あぁ そうだな｡ ｱﾂｱﾂだな｡
That's right. This is really warm.
(神楽)この肉 ﾎﾝﾄに肉ｱﾙか？
柔らかすぎるｱﾙよ！
Is this real meat? It's so tender!
Hey, hey! What are you doing?!
って おい！ なに食ってんだよ!?
いや 食べ物を粗末にしたら➡
Well, we're not supposed to waste food, are we?
ﾏｽﾞｲだろ？
(神楽)残り物には福があるｱﾙ！
Saving the best for last.
You guys are like pigs!
意地汚いんだよ！
毒でも入ってたら どうすんだよ!?
What will you do if there's poison in it?
Don't worry. There's no poison in it.
(獅子村)大丈夫だ
毒は入ってねえよ｡
(みんな)あぁっ！
(ｶﾘﾔ)ｺｲﾂらか？ 我らのことを➡
Are these the ones who have been sniffing around?
嗅ぎ回っているﾈｽﾞﾐというのは｡
(獅子村)はい ｶﾘﾔ様｡
Yes, Mr. Kariya.
(ﾌﾟｰ)ｵﾒｴ 加藤じゃねえか｡
何してんだ ｺﾗ｡
Kato, is that you?
What are you doing here?
W-Well...
い いやぁ…｡
っていうか お前らさ➡
Say, aren't you embarrassed for laying a trap like this?
こんなﾍﾞﾀな罠 仕掛けて
恥ずかしくねえの？
(下元)その ﾍﾞﾀな罠に
あっさりﾊﾏった お前らは➡
Speak for yourself! You're the ones that got caught!
恥ずかしくねえの？
(神楽)ｱﾀｼは もうちょっと➡
I prefer a little stronger flavor!
濃い目の味付けでも ｵｯｹｰ ｱﾙよ｡
(ﾌﾟｰ)人の話 聞け！
You listen to us!
おい お前たち！
ｶﾄｹﾝさんの契約書を返せ!!
Hey, you guys! Give us back Katoken's contract!
え？ 何それ｡
Huh?
What are you talking about?
そんなことのために
わざわざ 乗り込んできたの？
You're telling us you guys came all this way just for that?
…だから どうした！
So what if we did?
(笑い声)
獅子村の心配性が
事を大きくしたようだな｡
It looks like Shishimura overestimated them.
恐れ入ります｡
行くぞ 時間がない｡
Sorry about that.
Let's go. We don't have much time.
But what should I do with these guys?
しかし ｺﾔﾂらは…｡
Just throw them out.
(ｶﾘﾔ)捨てておけ｡
おい 加藤 安心しろよ｡
Don't worry, Kato.
もうすぐ 家だ なんだって
言ってられなくなるからよ｡
Soon, you won't have to worry about your house or anything else.
You'll get flattened in here anyway.
まぁ どうぜ お前たちは
ここで ﾍﾟｼｬﾝｺだけどな｡
(銀時たち)ﾍﾟｼｬﾝｺ？
ﾜﾝ！
Flattened?
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)ｺｰｽｹﾞｰﾄ ｵｰﾌﾟﾝ｡
Course gate open!
Higashi-Murayama One, prepare for launch.
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)東村山１号 発進位置へ｡
東村山１号 発進位置へ｡
Higashi-Murayama One, prepare for launch.
次 いってみよう！
だっふんだ！
Let's go!
Roger!
♪♪～
あぁっ！
(ｶﾘﾔ)よく見ておけよ｡
Enjoy this view while you can.
江戸の景色も
これが見納めだ｡
This is your last view of Edo.
ふぬ～～!! はぁ ﾀﾞﾒだ…｡
It's no use!
銀さんたちも
協力してくださいよ～！
Help me, you guys!
Hey, Kagura! Go help him.
おい 神楽！
お前 何とかしろって！
You're from the Yato clan, aren't you?
夜兎族なんだろ？
その手には乗らないね｡
I ain't falling for that.
I won't move until I finish all the food.
全部 食べるまで
てこでも動かないｱﾙよ｡
Geez.
まったく…｡ ん？
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさん！ どうして ここに!?
Elizabeth!
What are you doing here?
Ah, Zura must be here, right?
おっ ということは ﾂﾞﾗも一緒か｡
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない｡ 桂だ｡
It's not Zura. It's Katsura.
(桂)お前たちが
派手にやっているｽｷに➡
While you guys were living it up, we snuck in the back.
こちらも 裏から
忍び込ませてもらった｡
金庫を調べたら
あるものが出てきた｡
And we found something in the safe.
なに あったの!? ｶﾄｹﾝの契約書！
What? Did you find it? Is that Katoken's contract?
I don't know anything about that. But look at this.
そんなものは知らん｡
しかし これを見ろ｡
…あ ﾀﾞﾒかも｡
細かい字 弱いんだよね ｵﾚ｡
I would, but... I'm having a hard time with small print.
その書類 どう読む？ 銀時｡
What do you think about these documents, Gintoki?
皆目 見当もつかねえな｡
I have no idea.
ならば 教えよう｡
Then let me explain.
They intend to raze Edo to the ground.
ﾔﾂらは 江戸を
崩壊させようとしているのだ｡
What?!
江戸で 宴会？
崩壊だ ﾎﾞｹ～!!
They'll have a rave in Edo?
He said "raze," stupid!
はぁ…｡
かいつまんで 説明するとだな…｡
Let me give you a brief explanation.
(桂)ﾔﾂらは ｢地震のﾂﾎﾞ｣とでもいう
ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄを探し出し➡
They discovered an earthquake fault line
それを 天人のｶﾗｸﾘで
刺激することによって➡
and they stimulated that point with an Amanto-made device.
人工的に 巨大地震を起こし➡
It will cause a giant artificial earthquake.
江戸を
焦土と化そうとしているのだ｡
And Edo will be destroyed!
そ そんな…｡
Oh, no...
That sounds like some kind of evil anime organization.
まるで ｱﾆﾒの悪の組織みたいだな｡
でも いったい
何で そんなことを…？
But why would they do something like that?
ｶﾘﾔと つるんでいたﾔﾂらは
地上げ屋だ｡
Those people who were with Kariya are land sharks.
家をなくし
途方に暮れた人々から➡
They snatch up homes lost by others.
安く土地を
買いたたくつもりなのだ｡
狙いは 旧市街か？
And their goal is the old city?
Buildings that weren't constructed by Amanto are not very strong.
天人の技術を使用していない
建築物はもろい｡
大地震が起きれば おそらく
ひとたまりもないだろう…｡
If a big earthquake hits, they'll collapse in a moment.
ﾏｽﾞｲですよ！
このままじゃ 江戸が…！
Oh no! Edo will...
かといって そのﾂﾎﾞってﾔﾂが
どこだか わかんねえとな…｡
But we don't know where the point is.
何か 手がかりはないんですか！
Aren't there any clues?
いや さすがに そこまでは…｡
Well, unfortunately...
どうするんですか！
今から 江戸中 駆け回って➡
So what do we do now?
We don't have time to find the land sharks in Edo!
地上げ屋の居場所を探している
時間なんてないですよ｡
神楽！ もう食っただろ？
Kagura! You've had enough food, right?
とっとと 檻ぶっ壊せ!!
あいよ！
Break us out of this cage!
You got it!
ほわぁ～ちゃ～っ!!
っていうか 出られるなら
早くして!!
Why didn't you do this earlier?!
ｶﾄｹﾝ！
は… はいっ!?
Katoken!
Y-Yes!
お前の家 どこだ!?
Where is your house?
♪♪～
Hey, Gintoki!
おい 銀時！ どこへ行く!?
Where are you going?
お前らだけでは 危険だぞ！
It's dangerous if you go alone!
それでも行かなきゃならねえ
理由があんだよ！
I know, but we still have to go!
じゃあな ﾂﾞﾗ！
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ！
See you, Zura.
It's not Zura! It's Katsura!
銀さん
何がどうなってるんですか!?
Gin! What's going on?
要するに ﾔﾂらの目的は
江戸を さら地にして➡
Basically, their goal is to clear the land in Edo and then sell it at a higher price.
まとめて 地上げするって
寸法だろ？
そうですけど…｡
Right...
Then why did they clear Katoken's house first?
だったら なんで ｶﾄｹﾝの家
わざわざ先に地上げするんだ？
え～と それは…｡
Well...
I got it!
ああっ そうか！
地震のﾂﾎﾞってことですか!?
It's the earthquake fault line!
まっ そういうこった｡
じゃあ ｸﾋﾞになったり➡
That's right.
So he's fired and cheated and has his house taken away ...
土地を
だまし取られたりっていうのも!?
全部 ﾔﾂらが仕組んだんだろ｡
ひどい…！
All part of their plan.
That's terrible!
とにかく 飛ばすぞ！
はいっ！
Anyway, let's go!
Yah!
(加藤)あ あのぅ ちょっと…｡
Um...
なんだぁ？
言いたいことがあんなら➡
What is it?
If you have something to say, say it now!
今のうちに言っとけ～！
Right!
そうですよ！
一刻を争うんですから!!
We have no time to lose.
じゃあ 言いますけど…
道 間違ってますよ｡
Then I say... We're going the wrong direction.
(銀時/新八)ｳｿでしょ～!?
What?!
(ｶﾘﾔ)これこそ 我がﾄﾞﾘﾌﾄ星の
科学力をもって作られた➡
So, this is the Drift Star earthquake machine, hehe!
地震発生ﾏｯｽｨｰﾝ！
And this device will realize Mr. Kariya's ambition!
そして ｶﾘﾔ様の野望を叶える
夢のｶﾗｸﾘ｡
我らの時代が やってくるのです｡
Our time will come soon.
ﾌｯ 始めろ｡
はっ！
Begin!
All right!
(下元)削岩ﾋﾞｰﾑ照射！
目標ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄ到達まで あと10分!!
Rock drilling beam activated!
Ten minutes to reach the target!
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ！ いけ！
我らが野望とともに!!
Go! No one can stop us!
Intruders! Get them!
≪(武士)曲者だ～！
出あえ！ 出あえ～!!
What?
(近藤)御用あらためである！
(土方)真選組だ 神妙にしろ！
This is a raid!
We're the Shinsengumi! Calm yourselves!
ﾌｯ 幕府の犬が…！
Government dogs!
ほぅ 真選組と知って刃向かうか！
Oh, so you're ready to take on the Shinsengumi?
おもしろい！ 近藤 勲 参る!!
Interesting.
I'm Isao Kondo!
土方 十四郎 参る！
Toshiro Hijikata!
沖田 総悟 参る！
Sogo Okita!
Let's go!
続け～!!
(獅子村)ﾌｯ｡
(ｶﾘﾔ)そこまでだ！
Hold it right there!
何 言ってやがる！
What did you say? No, you hold it!
そこまでなのは
お前らのほうだろうが!!
何を勘違いしておる｡
Let me spell it out for you.
This is Drift Star territory.
ここは ﾄﾞﾘﾌﾄ星の
所有地であるぞよ｡
この家に 一歩でも踏み込んでみろ
国際問題になるぞ｡
If you take a single step into this house, it'll be an international incident.
ﾁｯ… 治外法権ってﾔﾂか…｡
Damn it! Extraterritoriality, huh?
ｸｿ～ｯ！ って
治外法権って 何だ？
Crap!
Anyway, what's extraterritoriality?
どうしても
家の中に入りたければ➡
If you want to get into the house, you need to go through official procedures.
正式な手続きを
踏んでもらおうか｡
(ｶﾘﾔの笑い声)
(土方)…って総悟 何やってんだ？
そりゃあ つまり➡
Sogo, what are you doing?
Well, if I tore down this house, we could go inside, right?
この家が なくなっちまえば
中に入れるってことでしょう？
一休さんか お前は！
Are you Mr. Ikkyu or something?
ﾌｯ わかったら
さっさと出ていってもらおうか｡
Feh... If you understand, then you'd better leave.
(近藤たち)ｸｯ…｡
(ｽｸｰﾀｰ音)
露払い ご苦労！
真打ちの登場だ!!
Thanks for the assistance! Make way for the star!
あれは…！
万事屋！
That's...
Odd Jobs?
ﾌｯ 来たか｡
He's here...
あとは任せな！
うわ～っ！
Leave the rest to us!
Hocha!
万事屋銀ちゃんが
万事 解決してやっからよ！
Odd Jobs Gin will take care of the problem!
うわぁ～っ!!
ほわちゃ～っ!!
Hocha!
なるほど！
旦那だったら やり放題だ！
I see. He can do whatever he likes!
I'm addicted...
(武士)ｸｾになりそう…｡
♪♪～
ｶﾘﾔ様 早く中へ｡
うむ｡
Mr. Kariya, let's go inside.
Wait!
待て！
お前とは 決着をつけたかった｡
It's time you and I settled this.
ﾍｯ ﾗｲﾊﾞﾙぶってんじゃねえよ
余興の練習君！
Huh, stop playing the role of my rival, Mr. Sideshow!
You!
このっ…！
Five minutes until we reach the target!
(下元)目標到達まで あと５分！
Good. Allow it to approach the epicenter and pull out!
(ｶﾘﾔ)よし！
震源ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄｱﾌﾟﾛｰﾁと同時に離脱だ！
Right!
ﾏｯｽｨｰﾝ 浮上！
Machine, surface!
♪♪～
An Earthquake?
地震!?
まさか もう!?
Did they already...?
なにっ!?
あい～ん！
うわ～っ!!
(神楽)ｷｬ～ｯ!!
♪♪～
何!? この いきなり
世界観ぶち壊すようなﾒｶは!!
What?
What the hell is this contraption? It could destroy the world!
ｽﾍﾟｼｬﾙだからって
調子にのってるｱﾙよ！
This is too much, even for a special two-part episode!
これが ﾂﾞﾗの言ってたｶﾗｸﾘか…｡
So this is the device that Zura was talking about?
(ｶﾘﾔの笑い声)
Excellent. Our plan is on the verge of success.
ご苦労だったな｡ だが まもなく
我々の計画は遂行される｡
ｸｿｯ！
このままじゃ 江戸の町が…！
No! Edo will...
新八！
Shinpachi!
お前の相手は このｵﾚだ！
この野郎…！
You'll have to fight me.
You...
Three minutes until we reach the target!
(下元)目標到達まで あと３分！
(笑い声)
M-My house...
わ… 私の家が…｡
えっ!?
What?
(神楽/新八)ｶﾄｹﾝ!?
(武士)ﾊﾞｶ！
Katoken!
Dumbass! Why did you leave him alone?
なんで ｱｲﾂをほっといたんだ！
Well, he looked really sick.
いや あんまり
影が薄かったから…｡
行け ｶﾄｹﾝ！ お前が止めるんだ!!
Go, Katoken! Stop them!
で… でも…｡
B-But...
(ﾌﾟｰ/下元)ﾍｯﾍｯﾍ…｡
ひぇ～っ!! ああっ…｡
ﾌﾝ！ 斬り捨ててくれるわ｡
I'll cut you down.
私は…｡
I-I...
逃げるんじゃねえ！
Don't run away!
まずは お前が変われ！
じゃなきゃ 何も変わらねえ!!
You have to change first, or nothing else will!
変わる…？
...Change...?
逃げても
逃げ切れるもんじゃねえ！
You can't run away!
Especially from those things you really want to forget!
特に…
本当に忘れたいことからはな！
♪♪～
((娘:お父さん…))
Daddy...
私は… 私は… 変わる…!!
I...
I...will change!
うぉぉ～っ!!
心頭滅却すれば 顔まで猪木～！
If I suppress my inner "self", my face will look just like Antonio Inoki's!
What?
なにっ!?
元気ですか～!!
How are you?
You're bluffing!
はったりだ!!
ﾋｼﾞを脇から離さない感じで➡
Keep my elbow to my side and just strike...
えぐり込むように…!!
おぉ～っ!!
Strike!
突くべ～し!!
あぁ～っ!!
Oh, this sucks!
(ｶﾘﾔ)ﾀﾞﾒだこりゃ～!!
(神楽/新八)やった～！
It worked!
(下元/ﾌﾟｰ)ｶﾘﾔ様！
(下元)早く 手当てを！
Mr. Kariya!
Help him!
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
I'm so proud of my student! He's become really strong!
さすがは 我が弟子！
強くなったｱﾙな｡
神楽ちゃんが教えたの
突きじゃなくて ｼﾞｬﾌﾞだったけどね｡
Kagura, you taught him to jab, not strike.
What are you doing, Katoken?
何してるｶﾄｹﾝ！
早く ｶﾗｸﾘを止めるんだ!!
Go and stop the earthquake machine now!
A-All right!
は はい…！
Um...
え～っと… これか!?
Is this it?
♪♪～
え～っ!? あと 50秒じゃなくて
２倍速だから 25秒!?
Fifty seconds left?! But the speed was doubled, so there's only twenty-five seconds left!
Hurry! Just stop it!
早く！ なんでもいいから
早く止めてよ～!!
Um... Is this it?
(加藤)えっと… これかな…？
Or this...?
This must be it!
これだ…！ ふぬ～っ…!!
折れた～!!
やっぱりか～！
It broke!
I knew that would happen! It broke!
やっぱり折れるのか～!!
Wait!
待て！ まだ 貴様との勝負が…！
We didn't finish our fight yet!
うっせえんだよ 三下！
Shut up, you flunkie! I don't have time to waste on you!
うだうだやってるﾋﾏはねえっと!!
一撃ですか…？
One hit and I'm down?
♪♪～
止まれ～!!
Stop!
と… 止まった…｡
I-It stopped...
Hey, let's get out of here!
おい 早く脱出だ！
は… はい！
A-All right!
(爆発音)
ひゃっほ～！
やった～！
Yahoo!
They did it!
(ｶﾘﾔたち)ひ～こら ひ～こら…｡
おい ｺﾗ！ その線から
一歩でも出てきたら➡
Hey, you know if you take a single step across that line you're no longer on foreign soil, right?
その 治外法権とやらじゃ
ねえんだろ？
(桂)ﾊｧﾊｧ… さすがだな 銀時…｡
Gintoki did a great job.
["Buy a car."]
腹痛ぇ…｡
My side hurts.
♪♪～
私たちの… 家が…｡
Our... house...
坂田さん…｡
Sakata...
Don't worry about your house.
なに 家なんて
なんとでもなるって｡
でも…｡
But...
ｱﾝﾀはもう 変わったんだろ？
You've changed, right?
…はい！
Yes!
♪♪～
(新八/神楽)あ～っ！
大和屋さんちの ｸﾛﾐちゃん！
ﾆｬ～ｵ｡
It's Kuromi of Yamatoya!
ｺﾗ ｸｿ猫！ 待ちやがれ～!!
Hey, you stupid cat, wait!
[Odd Jobs Gin]
あ～あ ｵﾚも 卍解とか
そういうのがあればなぁ…｡
Why can't I have a Bankai or something like that.
銀ちゃん ﾃﾚﾋﾞ観るｱﾙよ｡
あん？
Gin, look at the TV!
Samba! Oh, Katoken samba!
♪♪(加藤)｢ｻﾝﾊﾞ ｵ～ ｶﾄｹﾝｻﾝﾊﾞ」
おい これってまさか…？
Hey, can this be...
間違いないｱﾙ｡ ｶﾄｹﾝ ｱﾙよ！
That's it! That's Katoken!
Oh, yeah, Katoken's gaining popularity as a dancing enka singer.
あぁ ｶﾄｹﾝさん
最近 歌って縛れる演歌歌手って➡
芸能界を
のし上がってきたんですよ｡
Oh?
♪♪｢ｵ～ﾚ ｵ～ﾚ～｣
ﾌｯ… いい顔してるじゃねえか｡
He looks so happy!
♪♪(加藤)｢ｵ～ﾚ ｵ～ﾚ～｣
["To everyone at Odd Jobs Gin: I have my family back. Thanks a lot! -Kato"]
♪♪｢ｶﾄｹﾝｻﾝﾊﾞ！ ｵﾚ！｣
[Preview]
One year ago, I met this man.
He was too delicate to be a samurai
and his eyes were too honest for him to be a gangster.
The next episode:
"Nobody with Naturally Wavy Hair Can Be That Bad."
I forgot I was in the second part of the show.